Damir Yodgorov

dydamirbey@gmail.com (416) 720 0381 Toronto, ON View My Portfolio www.linkedin.com/in/damiryodgorov

PROFILE

Full Stack Developer with 3+ years of hands-on experience designing, developing, and implementing applications and solutions using a range of technologies and programming languages. Designed and developed web applications across multiple platforms, third-party integrations, and databases.

Databases: Oracle, PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB

Programming Languages: C, C++, C#, JavaScript, PHP,

XML

Operating Systems: Windows

Web Development: HTML5, CSS3, CSS Grid, Flexbox, Bootstrap 5, React + React Hooks, Redux, jQuery, JSON, Node.js, Express.js, NPM, RESTful API Design, SQL

Tools: MS Office, Dev C++, Visual Studio, Sublime Text, Atom, MS Visual Code, GitHub, SVN, Eclipse, Heroku, Netlify

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATES

Computer Programmer Diploma (CPD)2017 - 2019Seneca College, York CampusToronto, ON

Bachelor of Engineering, Computer EngineeringEastern Mediterranean University

North Cyprus

SMILE Certificate of Achievement
Seneca College, York Campus
Toronto, ON

ABET Certificate

Accreditation Board for Engineering and Technology

North Cyprus

WORK EXPERIENCE

Implementation Specialist/Computer Programmer VelocityEHS

May 2019 - Present Toronto, ON

- Create and configure applications for implementing SaaS solutions for clients
- Create dashboards, reports, notifications, web parts/widgets and components for the application using front-end (CSS, JS and JQUERY) and back-end (SQL, C#) tools
- Improve internal processes by creating standard reports, PDFs, imports, sites, and tools
- Investigate, diagnose, and resolve system and programming issues

Software Developer CJSC MDO- IMON INTERNATIONAL

May 2016 - July 2017 Khujand, Tajikistan

- With a team of 6 developers created ticket management system "Help Desk"
- Optimized company's website www.imon.tj.
- Analyzed client services data using SQL

Damir Yodgorov

dydamirbey@gmail.com (416) 720 0381 Toronto, ON View My Portfolio www.linkedin.com/in/damiryodgorov

PROJECTS

Smart Brain Web Application

- Experience Created a complex image recognition app using HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap 5, JavaScript, React + React Hooks, Node.js, Express.js, NPM, RESTful API Design, SQL and PostgreSQL. As well as used third-party AI (Artificial Intelligence) Clarifai API to detect the face on the picture.
- Application Summary The application allows users to register, sign in and upload any image and detect face if exists. In addition, users can update their information on the profile page including passwords. Furthermore, there is an administrator who has complete control of the application. The administrator, can monitor the activities of every user, delete, create, and update information about any user in the system.

Expense Tracker

- **Experience** Using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, and React + React Hooks created an expense tracker web application where users can manage their expenses.
- Application Summary Using the application user can add expenses that have name and cost, remove expenses, view the remaining budget, view how much they have spent, edit a budget, and search expenses. The application helps to have control over every expense and maintain healthy financial status.

Immigration Guideline

- **Experience** Using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQUERY, Bootstrap, SQL, and PHP created a web application that acts as a guideline for immigrants in the Russian Federation.
- Application Summary The app was like the government website where users were able to stay updated with news, ask a question from an Immigration Officer, and get information regarding their immigration process.

VOLUNTEERING

SMILE Mentor Seneca College, York Campus

Sept 2018 - April 2019 Toronto, ON

- Taught students the fundamental logic of programming
- Helped students learn to program in an easy and fun way
- Helped students deal with issues in Academic areas
- Prepared and submitted monthly report about each student